<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rayyip</title><link>https://rjrobben.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on rayyip</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:56:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rjrobben.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>From Law to Computer Science</title><link>https://rjrobben.github.io/abouts/law_and_cs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:56:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjrobben.github.io/abouts/law_and_cs/</guid><description>As someone who has studied both law and computer science, I have come to realize that my true passion lies in the latter field. While a law degree can certainly be valuable in terms of developing people skills and the ability to interpret and apply rules and concepts, I have found that my interests lie more in exploring the universe through the lens of computer science and programming.
Teach You how to Think vs the Dullness of Law Link to heading One of the most powerful conceptual frameworks in computer science is the use of graphs, which can be used to model everything from protein structures to social networks and even the human body.</description></item><item><title>Vimtex Viewer cannot find Zathura window ID</title><link>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/vimtex_debug/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 11:15:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/vimtex_debug/</guid><description>Problems encountered Link to heading Today I have tried fixing vimtex error in my machine by exploring its source code. The error I faced is &amp;ldquo;viewer cannot find Zathura window ID.&amp;rdquo; I have no idea how I get this error at first. Because I have already installed Zathura on wsl, (plus a bunch of other sofwares, e.g. vcsxrv, x11-apps) and the zathura is working on my wsl. I can open a pdf window in wsl terminal to view documents in windows.</description></item><item><title>About this blog</title><link>https://rjrobben.github.io/abouts/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 20:57:29 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjrobben.github.io/abouts/about/</guid><description>Hello, world! Link to heading I will be using this site to record my daily thoughts and learning. I feel that it is a good idea to organize my messy thoughts and progress into a blog. It would not only be a database of my thoughts and things I reached online (and offline) but also encourage me to express my ideas.
Reading makes a full man, meditation a profound man, discourse a clear man.</description></item></channel></rss>