<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Ray Dylan</title><link>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Ray Dylan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 14:05:53 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making an Android Arrival Widget for bus</title><link>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/bus-arrival-widget/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 14:05:53 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/bus-arrival-widget/</guid><description>Motivation Link to heading The current bus app are provided by the major bus comapny in my location, which are KMB and CityBus. These apps have a pretty long loading time along with the advertisement time.
It takes around 20 seconds from unlocking to phone to seeing the arrival time of the bus route on screen. I hope to create a widget that can periodically fetch data for a particular stop from the bus arrival time api, to display directly the arrival time on my screen.</description></item><item><title>工作時的修行</title><link>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/%E5%B7%A5%E4%BD%9C%E6%99%82%E7%9A%84%E4%BF%AE%E8%A1%8C/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 13:27:45 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/%E5%B7%A5%E4%BD%9C%E6%99%82%E7%9A%84%E4%BF%AE%E8%A1%8C/</guid><description>我有一個嚴重的問題：經常在走神，分心。當在做A時，心就冒起很多其他BCDEFG，一個個念頭，陸續有來，不斷彈出，然後我有會跟隨每一個念頭，鑽入Rabbit Hole，以至我根本沒有時間去完成A。
工作時，因為心正在想，在顧慮，腦在不斷思考: 工作的事情，要做什麼，不想做，網上的資源，各種念頭，學習的欲望，性，感慨，時而傷感，時而委屈，經常不知所措。有一百件事情想做，卻不能集中於任何一件，以至一事無成。
在佛教有一個詞語形容：掉舉。冥想時這個情況也時常出現，在禪修一書中指出 —— 掉舉的解藥正是「知足」。
工作時禪修 Link to heading 就像冥想前和自己説：「當下覺知，當下覺知，當下覺知」。在做X時，也可和自己説：「X，X，X」。例如，現在我想做Arrival Widget，就先提醒自己，「整Arrival Widget， 整Arrival Widget， 整Arrival Widget」。然後，就和冥想一樣，嘗試只與這個單一所緣在一起，分心時就用對付五蓋的辦法對付分心。例如，對X發展知足的心，對做X感到知足時，去對付掉舉。</description></item><item><title>What is recursion from a beginner's view</title><link>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/recursion_beginner/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 18:40:41 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/recursion_beginner/</guid><description>I always find recursion a difficult concept to grasp, mainly because it&amp;rsquo;s hard to visualize or understand what is exactly going on when you call a function recursively. The recursions can easily go complicated because from the start to the base case (meaning reaching a point where there will be no more recursion) there can be tons of steps. A several layers recursion is already computationally demanding for my brain to visualize.</description></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 21:52:48 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/introduction/</guid><description>Hello, world! Link to heading I will be using this site to record my daily thoughts and learning. I feel that it is a good idea to organize my messy thoughts and progress into a blog. It would not only be a database of my thoughts and things I reached online (and offline) but also encourage me to express my ideas.
Reading makes a full man, meditation a profound man, discourse a clear man.</description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 20:57:29 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rjrobben.github.io/posts/hello-world/</guid><description> HI everyone. Link to heading</description></item></channel></rss>